again for a lot all right so you don't
look everything just lit up we'll give
people up at a time to come in here for
those of you who don't know beer comedy
I this is our open source driving
attempt open palette let's drive the car
right now
and this isn't some fake stuff you can
what everything you see here is already
public you can just go download it this
is an eon you can buy a shop a shop
comet REI
that's very nice now of course since
this is a YouTube live we're about to
show you something that that's not
public so maybe you guys will find it
exciting
blink are here a little bit to the right
and it'll automatically change lanes
[Music]
so you see here with another curve going
left see how it does lead to her
you go downstream eel I'll share the
wheel
there are 15 people we got 15 people to
do this away for a few more people
demonstrated again all make a u-turn
[Music]
yeah bucks you want to see the steering
wheel so how do you do yeah so it's not
um it's it's automatic but it requires
you to look it doesn't know when it's
safe to make the lane change that's your
job as a person
[Music]
spin the car around I'm here
get some viewers
I don't even think I think that I'm
gonna do for myself does that's how I've
always done in the past you don't have
to anymore a walks Harris has kicked up
blind spot monitors it's not linked to
the blind spot monitors yet so any of
the cars that you can get them on we're
gonna add it in before their ships live
and for reference guys this is e zero
seven feature so this you're gonna see a
few open pilot releases without this
there's more to this feature then that
just Lane changing
but just Lane changing is all we're
gonna demonstrate for you guys today
watch the I don't know if you guys have
seen them at the full self-driving Tesla
video
[Music]
full self-driving cast the video is very
inspiring and I think we'd like to be
Tesla to shipping all those things see
what a ship full self-driving maybe
maybe some scope he's not what Tesla
promised you guys what a Tesla promise
this year no no it shouldn't be say yeah
yeah it's very alpha feature but if you
guys watched my maybe it doesn't say you
can and we should be able to use the
blind spot monitors on the Toyotas yeah
- oh and it's still doing it yeah we
kind of any hacks to detect when the
lane changes over not so I know there's
some Forks with lane changes um this is
not hacks this is trained on probably a
million lane changes that you guys did
in real life
[Music]
yeah yeah I think I think in order to
make this model it has watched you
humans users of open violent to 100,000
Lane changes and that's how it learns to
do the perfect lane change for every
situation so yeah there's a secret input
to the model that we normally set it to
driving straight but when we do the lane
change we just ask the model to do a
lane change so there's a question how is
speed controlled during the lane change
and so that we don't do anything special
with the with the speed but once it
starts doing the lane change deletes
should switch very aware
[Music]
here's a full blinker on gotta watch
that guy in my rearview ya little notchy
change lunch automatically change
I wish we can I wish we could all return
the blinker oh yeah that would be nice
yeah so we could yeah we could keep
doing it oh we're back we're back
yeah I think I'm in the mill yeah and
then start
yeah and now we'll cancel yes yeah yeah
feels like it like costs that's the
beauty of neural networks that was all
fuzzy
and you can make multiple languages just
give it one notch for this one change
lanes yeah you get one notch for this
one change legs again yes at the
procedure she turned on the blinker and
then you get for the lodge when you
think it's clear and this is how we're
gonna proceed with a lot of these sort
of features right my experience in
navigator autopilot is that it increased
anxiety in a lot of ways because you
borrow a sure when the car was gonna
make the lane change I'm sitting there
and I'm like from my perspective it
looks totally clear I have no idea why
the car isn't going on part of that can
be fixed with communication but part of
that is you want to be in control of
everyone on some magic wand
everyone wants a wand that they can wave
and like make the leg change right but
they don't want the wand to tell them
what wishes they want
no okay ideally it would monitor your
blind spot and tell you what it's safe
to go with you just have to press you
know engage Captain Picard but uh but I
kind of like the steering wheel to
acknowledge that engage it's like it's a
nice button - yeah now this is not in
devel right now this is a very very
early preview of CRO seven there's gonna
be a bunch more sera 6 releases first
we've actually stripped these weights
out of the model so good luck trying to
add it yourself
there's a secret 512 dimensional vector
that will enable a change can I scroll
back you guys are killing it thanks guys
I can't see all the messages I wish I
bought it when they didn't
this the time of day affect the lane
change performance not children the way
this thing learned to change lanes by
watching all of your lanterns so if all
of your lane changes happen at all times
of the day yeah yeah you have to keep
the blinker on right now during the lane
change but that might change maybe it's
like 50 yeah like everything is deep
learning yeah this needs some work they
wanted to go for the double yeah we need
a better way to detect when the lane
change is down which it's done yeah and
now we have some hacky way by looking at
the lane oh yeah I guess yeah I guess
that was the problem we just thought it
was yeah this should be and this is an
example of like people think open pilot
is only for the highway but
this guy off just because I find
speeding people think about is only for
the highway it's not I it works decently
well
[Music]
yes yes Larissa text Xtreme command to
turn the blinkers on but that's like a
ferry debug a command and it stops
working when the car moves so maybe just
a different one but haven't found it
[Music]
yeah but then the stalk is still there
so no I mean maybe if you put it in a
debug mode well it won't work anymore
but no I'm wondering is there a way to
electronically pop the stalk or is that
yeah I think it's mechanical hmm yeah I
mean my parents new BMW it's just not
physical anymore
so I just like a double press talk
but Alexi sets its mechanic OMA oh yeah
maybe that's the wrong it's like really
weird oh yeah oh we're gonna make a
small detour it's weird like yes I made
a mistake I have to make like three
rights not a mistake so any more
questions about the lane change 24
people I guess we didn't post on Twitter
yeah well 24 people apparently and it
was nice about disco feast and everyone
got a notification oh it was Twitter
related so a while ago apparent you said
we're we're never gonna ship automatic
lane change and what changed all right
so you ever changed
Tesla we're never gonna ship stop signs
until Tesla does okay so we're like you
know we use a waste of time to even
think about stop signs until Tesla's
figured it out right cuz maybe it's
really hard and we can let them figure
out whether it's really hard or not but
they've already figured out lane changes
and it actually turns out to be easy
let's say oh look at this a lane change
through an intersection
see now what can do that only us
so we were never gonna ship adjustable
following distance we can I say we were
never gonna ship automatic lane change I
don't know maybe you then it's not it's
it's it's um you do the lane jam it does
it for you but yeah I think we should
called assisted Lane in this thing
that's like much more regulated friendly
yeah Greg came up with that I like it
yeah yeah that's like automatic is that
a real thing or did like or make that up
I think us are in the minute all right
Thank You scobie's oh when it's the next
minecraft stream Oh actually I was
thinking but maybe nap first in those
dream not all in craft um Hank
alright